<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Teaching | speak softly, and carry Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/categories/teaching/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-01T20:42:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Gilbert]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kgilbert.cmu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picking the Right Fight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/picking-the-right-fight/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T02:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/picking-the-right-fight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in Roni&#8217;s class we talked about picking fights. I think you&#8217;re within 
your rights to tackle your problem any way you want, but it&#8217;s an important 
battle to &#8220;pick the right fight&#8221;. </p>

<!-- more -->

<p>What I mean about &#8220;picking the right fight&#8221; in statistics, is to tread carefully
when you make conclusions about the analysis. Often, we&#8217;re trying to show or 
prove or disprove or undermine or support some claim given some data about
the claim. So let&#8217;s say we&#8217;ve performed some experiment and have two binary questions: 
Do we have enough data, and do we have low error?</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Option 1:
If you have tons of data and you have very low error, you should <strong>GO HOME</strong>. 
There&#8217;s nothing else to be done here. Finish up, because you aren&#8217;t
going to come up with anything interesting any more. Honestly, what could 
be more perfect? This is like the ideal, frictionless scenario.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Option 2: 
If you have not a lot of data and you have very high error, you should <strong>GO HOME</strong>.
There&#8217;s nothing which <strong>can</strong> be done here. It&#8217;s an abysmal situation. 
You can either continue to make poor predictions, or you could just start making 
shit up. Either way, you have to rethink your strategy. This is where picking the right fight comes in later.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Option 3:
If you have a lot of data but you have very high error, you should <strong>CRY</strong>.
You dun goofed. Either your data is totally irrelevant (you should do more 
statistical analysis), your algorithm is terrible (you should do more 
statistical analysis), or you did something terribly wrong. More statistical 
analysis wouldn&#8217;t hurt.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Option 4:
If you don&#8217;t have a lot of data but you have very low error, you should be <strong>SKEPTICAL</strong>.
It&#8217;s a fluke, do the test again. Don&#8217;t buy in to thinking that there&#8217;s a practically 
significant relationship between children&#8217;s shoe sizes and their IQ. You&#8217;re not thinking
through this clearly enough and you&#8217;re making mistakes along the way.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="so-what-option-are-you">So what option are you?</h2>

<p>Personally, I like being put into situation #2. There is some sort of morbid pleasure 
in being able to wreak order out of chaos. But if you&#8217;re going to go down that path, 
you need to be aware that you can only take those risks by picking the right fight. 
How could we rectify the situation (pick a better fight) if we have too little data to speak of?
How about bootstrapping more samples? How do we sample a more variable population if our
current data is too homogenous? How about bootstrapping the residuals? </p>

<p>OK, maybe you can just solve all of your problems by bootstrapping. Thanks 402.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
