<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Geoparser | speak softly, and carry Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/categories/geoparser/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-01T21:53:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Gilbert]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kgilbert.cmu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on Schedule]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/back-on-schedule/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T02:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/back-on-schedule</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- more -->

<p>Today is the first time since February that I&#8217;m actually pushing something 
onto Octopress. Skimming over much of my Junior Spring semester at CMU, I was 
monstrously busy with some difficult classes (<a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~roni/10601/">Roni&#8217;s Machine Learning</a> 
and <a href="http://www.stat.cmu.edu/~cshalizi/uADA/13/">Cosma&#8217;s 402</a> just to name a few), 
then throw on top of that the <a href="http://www.cmusigmachi.org">Lambda Pi chapter</a>&#8217;s 
first semester of operation as a chapter. We held our first <a href="http://dd.cmusigmachi.org/">Derby Days</a> 
(<a href="https://github.com/sethvargo">Seth Vargo</a> deserves a mention for his 
incredible job on that website, which he did mostly alone), initiated our 
first class (for which I had the honor of being Ritual Chairman), graduated 
our first Seniors, and earned ourselves our first 
<a href="http://www.sigmachi.org/province-balfour-award">Province Balfour Award</a> (again, Seth). 
This summer, I&#8217;m looking forward to representing my fraternity chapter as the 
Delegate to our Grand Chapter held in Washington, D.C., and I might be making 
a cameo appearance at <a href="http://balfourltw.sigmachi.org/">BLTW</a>.</p>

<p>This summer, I&#8217;m back to work at CMU with another research division. For the 
next two months I&#8217;ll be doing geoparsing with <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~gelern/">Judith Gelernter</a> in LTI. 
The project has a lot of interesting background on social media interactons 
and I&#8217;m hoping it&#8217;ll give me lots of table-talk in the future, to piggy-back 
my previous research work at CMU. Recruiters love hearing about the weird 
stuff you can accomplish with current statistics methods. It&#8217;s like a weird 
arms race of who can come up with the most terrifying implications for user data.</p>

<p>Other than that, it seems like nothing has really changed since the beginning 
of the year, and it doesn&#8217;t even seem like it was that long ago. The only 
noticable difference that I can tell is that I&#8217;m using Spotify now instead of 
Pandora and I&#8217;m living with 4 of my brothers in an off-campus house instead 
of with 15 of my brothers in the Sigma Chi house.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
