<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | speak softly, and carry Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-01T01:45:06-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Gilbert]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kgilbert.cmu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World! Octopress is finally running!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/hello-world-octopress-is-finally-running/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T14:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.speaksoftly.us/blog/hello-world-octopress-is-finally-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have pretty much no idea what business I have writing a blog. I have a terrible
attention span to writing. I think it looks really tacky when a blog goes
weeks or months in between posts. To make matters worse, I&#8217;m not super 
thrilled with my choice of domain (on the <code>.us</code> TLD), but there was a $3.99 sale 
at <a href="http://name.com">name.com</a> and I felt like it was a decent price. It gives 
me a little bit of a playground to play in without shelling out a dozen bucks
for a &#8220;real&#8221; <code>.com</code> website. </p>

<p>Getting Octopress set up was in and of itself an endeavor, but I&#8217;ll get the 
hang of it as time goes on. The host I&#8217;m using only lets me use static HTML 
files so Octopress was a very ideal system. It took maybe 16 hours to get the 
whole thing together. I had major issues with Ruby installation and raking 
files correctly. I&#8217;m pretty sure I still hate the command <code>bundle install</code>. 
I highly recommend those following in my footsteps to use <code>yari</code>.</p>

<p>One of the other things that attracted me to a blog was being able to publish code 
snippets in Markdown. Since I&#8217;ve gotten into using Markdown for my text files, 
I&#8217;ve started to enjoy just&#8230; writing Markdown. It&#8217;s kind of fun, and everything
comes out looking so nice. <a href="http://www.github.com/sethvargo">Seth</a> and I want to
port our chapter&#8217;s bylaws to Markdown so they&#8217;re not mired in the bullshit <code>.docx</code> 
they&#8217;re languishing in now. Not to say we&#8217;ll be publishing <code>LaTeX</code> in fraternity bylaws, 
but the Office format bothers me. A lot.</p>

<h2 id="speak-softly-and-carry-big-data">Speak Softly, and carry Big Data.</h2>

<p>As for the blog, I&#8217;m only here to talk about things that I&#8217;m really passionate 
about. Yes, a lot of that will come from my professional work. Expect lots of statistics,
math, some physics, and tons of programming thrown in. But I&#8217;ll also be here to
write about some of the stuff I get engaged with, and probably mention a lot of the 
Sigma Chi stuff I get involved in.</p>

<p>What else could be more important?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
